# **Rimple Poonia Dabas**

**Data Analytics** – University of Toronto | **MTech** – IIT Delhi, India | **MSc.** (Physics) – Panjab University, India **Toronto, Canada** | Email: <a href="mailto:rimpledabas@gmail.com">rimpledabas@gmail.com</a> | Ph: +1 (437) 229 6601 | Permanent Resident in Canada **GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/RimpleDabas">https://github.com/RimpleDabas</a> | **LinkedIn:** <a href="https://github.com/in/rimpledabas">https://github.com/RimpleDabas</a> | **LinkedIn:** <a href="https://github.com/in/rimpledabas">https://github.com/in/rimpledabas</a> | **LinkedIn:** <a href="https://github.com/in/rimpledabas">https://github.com/in/rimpledabas</a> | **LinkedIn:** <a href="https://github.com/in/rimpledabas">https://github.com/in/rimpledabas</a> | <a href="

Analyst with background in Physics and research. Performance driven business analytics professional experience encompassing Data Science, Analytics, Statistical modeling, and BI Integration in different industries. Master's degree from IIT Delhi (Top 10 IT College in India) and certificate from University of Toronto in Data Analytics and Visualizations. Team oriented individual with strong organizational, administrative, and analytical skills.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript, HTML, MATLAB, NOSQL, VBA

Applications: Power BI, Tableau, MySQL, PostgreSQL, API, Flask, MongoDB

Tools: Excel, PowerPoint, Scikit Learn, Pandas, NumPy, TensorFlow, Jupyter Notebook

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Research and Teaching Assistant**

2020-2022

York University, Toronto, Canada

- Collected, cleaned, and transformed data to get insights using Excel and Python
- Created reports and presentations to present summary of the findings with PowerPoint
- Created summarized dashboards and automated them for routine presentation purposes
- Did Statistical and linear regression analysis to get insights from the data
- Development of machine learning methods using supervised learning using Python and Tensorflow.

#### **Data and Business Analyst**

2017-2020

### 24 7 Technologies, Nebraska, USA

- Extracted data using SQL queries for further analysis using BI tools and track Key point Indicators
- Developed ETL process of SQL to aggregate data and write stored procedures and views
- Compiled and cleaned data from various sources, analyzed the data to create in-depth reports
- Conduct EDA and created visualizations using Python to help make performance driven decisions.
- Developed reports and dashboards to gain insights and increase operational efficiency
- Created reports to help gain insights with Power BI and Excel
- Developed self service dashboards using PowerBI to help teams make decisions faster.

# Assistant Professor, Physics & Electronics Delhi University, Delhi, India

2013-2017

- Taught Network Analysis, Python, C++, Mathematical Physics to undergraduate students
- Helped students in completion of projects using programming languages such as Python, Excel
- Created reports for administrative purposes using MS-word to keep track of students performances
- Prepared presentations for students using PowerPoint and gained strong communication skills
- Led class activities both large and small group to foster growth in course concepts
- Commended by professor and department chair for creative instructional activities and patience
- Developed leadership skills and provided guidance to 300+ students.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### Flower Detection App. | University of Toronto

Developed an app to allow users to upload an image and give results for the flower.

 Skills: Python, Sci-kit Learn, TensorFlow, Flask, Web scraping, HTML, JavaScript, HTML, Machine learning, PowerPoint

- Collected flower images from Google Images, Pixabay and Flickr using web scraping and API calls
- Used Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) for training the model with TensorFlow & Keras to get 79% accuracy.

# Interactive visualizations for Canadian Rental Market | University of Toronto

Developed and deployed an app for Canadian rental market analysis with multi tab dashboard.

- Skills: Python, Flask, NumPy, Pandas, SQL, MongoDB, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, PowerPoint,
- Used JavaScript libraries such as D3.js, leaflet, charts.js for creating interactive dashboards
- Used Mongo Atlas for creating non-relational database to house and retrieve the data.

# **ETL IMDB | University of Toronto**

Extracted IMDB data to create API end points

- Skills: Python, Flask, NumPy, Pandas, SQL, Web scraping, PostgreSQL, SQL Alchemy
- Used Python package 'Beautiful Soup' for web scraping IMDB to extract information
- Created relational database using PostgreSQL for the top 250 IMDB TV series & Emmy awards.

#### Rental Market Analysis | University of Toronto

Conducted exploratory data analysis for rental analysis

- Skills: Excel, Python, Matplotlib, Pandas, NumPy, Seaborn, API, PowerPoint
- Cleaned and transformed data for visualizations using Excel and Python
- Created visualizations to get the market trends over the past five years with Pandas and Matplotlib.

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Toronto Indian Institute of Technology (IIT), Delhi Panjab University Certificate, Data Analytics MTech, Applied Optics MS(Physics) Toronto | Feb'23-Aug'23 Delhi, India | 2010-12 Chandigarh, India | 2004-09

# **OTHER ACHIEVEMENTS**

- Secured 2nd position in MTech. Applied Optics batch of 2012 at IIT Delhi
- Secured all India rank 21 out of 100K plus in the National Eligibility Test (NET) for Lectureship in India
- Secured all India rank 427 out of 50K plus in the Graduate Aptitude Test in Engineering (GATE).